Guide to the Henry Hill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Henry Hill papers
1812-1829
MS 680
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
Correspondence and business papers of Henry Hill, merchant, U.S. consul at Valparaiso and Santiago, Chile, and officer of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. The papers deal largely with Hill's business affairs and travels in Europe and South America and consist of two letterbooks containing copies of letters from Hill to members of his family, friends, and business associates, 1812-1815 and 1817-1818. Also included are three volumes of letters (ca. 929 items) from Estanislao Lynch, Hill's Chilean business partner, 1817-1829, dealing almost exclusively with business ventures and politics in Chile and Peru. There are also typewritten copies of some of the letters.
Hill, Henry, 1795-1892
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Hiram Bingham, ca. 1904.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Hill: merchant of New York, Liverpool, Peru, and Chile; U.S. Consul at Santiago and Valparaiso, Chile, 1818-; treasurer of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence and business papers of Henry Hill, merchant, U.S. consul at Valparaiso and Santiago, Chile, and officer of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. The papers deal largely with Hill's business affairs and travels in Europe and South America and consist of two letterbooks containing copies of letters from Hill to members of his family, friends, and business associates, 1812-1815 and 1817-1818. Also included are three volumes of letters (ca. 929 items) from Estanislao Lynch, Hill's Chilean business partner, 1817-1829, dealing almost exclusively with business ventures and politics in Chile and Peru. There are also typewritten copies of some of the letters.
Business; Chile -- History -- War of Independence, 1810-1824; Latin America; Peru -- History -- War of Independence, 1820-1829; United States -- Commerce -- Chile; United States -- Commerce -- England; United States -- Foreign relations -- Chile; Businessmen; Diplomats; Merchants; Hill, Henry, 1795-1892; Lynch, Estanislao
- Inventory
  - Letterbooks
    - ca. 1812 Aug-1815 Dec (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1817 Apr-1818 Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Typewritten copies of letters
    - 1812 Aug-1813 Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1817 Apr-Jun (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1817 Jul-Aug (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1817 Sep-Oct (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1817 Nov 3-14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Estanislao Lynch
    - 1817 Jul-1819 Jul (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1819 Aug-1820 Aug (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1820 Sep-1829 Jun (Box 3, Folder 10)